<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speciation on Kieran Samuk, PhD</title>
    <link>https://ksamuk.github.io/tags/speciation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speciation on Kieran Samuk, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Kieran Samuk</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/speciation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombination and Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://ksamuk.github.io/project/recombination-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ksamuk.github.io/project/recombination-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genetic architecture of adaptation is thought to be a result of the interplay between natural selection, gene flow and the structure of the genome. One example of this is the localization of adaptive alleles in regions of low recombination, particularly when adaptation occurs in the face of gene flow. To test this idea, my colleagues and I created a large dataset of genomic data from pairs of stickleback populations from around the world that vary in the presence of gene flow and divergent selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speciation Genomics</title>
      <link>https://ksamuk.github.io/project/speciation-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ksamuk.github.io/project/speciation-genomics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Speciation is the process by which reproductive isolation evolves between two lineages. What is the genetic basis of reproductive isolation? How important is natural selection in this process? I am applying a combination of genomic and traditional evolutionary tools to study these questions in a very young species: the white stickleback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;white-sticklebacks&#34;&gt;White sticklebacks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White sticklebacks are a type of marine threespined stickleback found exclusively in Nova Scotia, Canada. They are often found alongside &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; marine threespined sticklebacks, from which they are distinguished in several ways, notably white (instead of blue) nuptial colour of males and a complete lack of parental care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
